These are exams we each take separately,
本来　一人一人で受けるはずの試験
なのに　いろんな人と同じ舞台に立っているのを感じる
and yet we still feel like we're entering the same arena as many others:
those we fight beside,
一緒になって戦う者
those we fight against,
敵となって戦う者
やじと声援を飛ばすギャラリー
and the onlookers who cheer and jeer.
これは　まるで…
This is almost like...
We are assassins.
僕らは　暗殺者
おまけに　今はグラディエーター
But right now we're also gladiators.
戦いの鐘が…
Today, the bell signals the start of a battle.
今日は鳴る
テストはいい
Tests are a good thing.
The knowledge gained from a night of cramming
一夜漬けで得た知識など
大人になったら　ほとんど忘れてしまうだろう
will be all but forgotten once you hit adulthood.
それでいい
And that's fine.
The experience you gain through competition,
同じルールの中で　力を磨き　脳みそを広げ　結果を競う
having sharpened your skills and broadened your minds
その結果から得る経験こそ　宝物だ
all under the same set of rules...
That is the real treasure.
は…速い
So fast!
中間より　ずっと
It's so much tougher than midterms!
At a combined junior-senior high prep school,
中高一貫の進学校では
it's not unusual for junior-high students to start
learning at a high-school level during third year.
中３から高校の範囲を習い始めることは珍しくない
The fastest-paced subjects at our school are English, math, and science.
特にペースが速いのは　うちでは　英　数　理
けど　学校内での条件は　皆同じだ
But the same conditions apply to us all.
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on!
起立
礼
ロックオン
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on!
起立
礼
ロックオン
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
sensei target on
The target is our teacher!
せんせー
ターゲットオン
potential takai
We've got a lot of potential
ポテンシャル高い
hodo mendokusai
It's just that we're not trying
ほどめんどくさい
dropout mentality
We had that dropouts' mentality
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
hinichijou wo ryougashi
No matter the unusual situation we were in
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
非日常を凌駕し
僕らはうたたね顔して
bokura wa utatatanegao shite
We pretended to doze off
knife kakushimotta
While holding on to a hidden knife
翻译...兰樱
校对...Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..兰樱
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
起立
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on
礼
ロックオン
hottokeba kitto dareka yatte kureru to
Thinking someone would deal with you eventually
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...歪歪
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
doko ka taningoto datta
We didn't really feel invested in the job
どこか　他人事だった
だけど
dakedo
But now
だけど
mister teacher oshiete mikansei na bokura
Teacher, teach us, we're still growing up
Mr.ティーチャー教えて　未完成の僕ら
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
anata to iu furaku no target uchinukeru deshou ka
Will we be able to shoot through an invincible target like you?
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
idomu tabi ni kanousei ga afureta
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
Our chances soar each time we challenge you
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
idomu tabi ni kanousei ga afureta
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
挑む限り
可能性はハーフ＆ハーフ
mister teacher mite ite mayoi ooki bokura
Teacher, watch us, as we try to find a direction in life
Mr.ティーチャー見ていて　迷い多き僕ら
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
dare yori mo anata no tame ni moubenkyouchuu sa
We're studying our ass off for you more than anybody else
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
殺意だけが
satsui dake ga anata e no message
Only the bloodlust is our message to you
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
殺意だけが
あなたへのメッセージ
jiriki gachi de hongan iku yo
We'll make our dreams come true on our own for real
あなたへのメッセージ
自力　ガチで
本願　行くよ
revolution
A revolution!
レボリューション
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
レボリューション
sensei target on
The target is our teacher!
せんせー
ターゲットオン
Episode
School's
Out
Time
1st
Term
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 及微博 @诸神字幕组
これがラスト問題か
So this is the last problem?
Those scrubs!
雑魚どもが
I spent a year in Los Angeles
when my folks worked there.
俺は　親の仕事で　ＬＡに１年いた
いまさら　中学レベルでつまずくかよ
There's no way any junior-high level stuff
will trip me up now!
If you want to know the truth,
I felt like slapping the cook's face
a hundred times.
If you want to know the truth,
I felt like slapping the cook's face
a hundred times.
If you want to know the truth,
I felt like slapping the cook's face
a hundred times.
If you want to know the truth,
I felt like slapping the cook's face
a hundred times.
If you want to know the truth,
I felt like slapping the cook's face
a hundred times.
If you want to know the truth,
I felt like slapping the cook's face
a hundred times.
It's not going down? What the...
倒れない
嘘だろ　満点解答の見本だぞ
That was a textbook answer!
A little stiff, don't you think?
お堅いねぇ
Don't try so hard, Honor Roll!
力抜こうぜ　優等生
Honestly, I wanted to give
that cook a hundred slaps in the face.
A perfect score? From the E Class?!
満点解答　Ｅ組ごときが
I'm guessing you never read
Salinger's "The Catcher in the Rye."
たぶん　読んでないっしょ　サリンジャーの『ライ麦畑でつかまえて』
Leave it to a fine school to
come up with some fine questions.
さすが名門校　いい問題を作りますね
The questions cite famous literature.
問題文が名作から引用されている
生徒の読書量や臨機応変さも採点基準に加える気でしょう
They'll want the scoring standard to include how much a student reads and how adaptable she can be.
They'll probably lose points if they don't answer in the same rough and concise colloquial style as the source text.
おそらくは　原文に準じた雑で簡潔な口語体で答えなければ減点になる
Honestly, I wanted to give
that cook a hundred slaps in the face.
I did it!
やった
Damn! Our English teacher only mentioned that novel in passing in the middle of class!
しまった　その小説　英語の教師が授業中さりげなく勧めてやがった
I guess you didn't have many
friends overseas, eh, Seo-kun?
外国でいい友達いなかったっしょ　瀬尾君
やたら　熱心に本を勧めるタコとかさ
Like an octopus who practically
pushed books onto you?
I've always admired this kind of subtle rebellion.
先生　こういう繊細な反逆に憧れてましてね
ぜひ２カ国語で読んでください
You simply must read it in both languages.
君たちの年頃なら　キュンキュンくるはずです
It ought to strike a real chord with you at your age.
Dammit!
くそ
そ～ら　理科は暗記だ
Ha! Science is all about memorization!
何　装甲が剥がせない
Huh? I can't get its armor off!
But I know I memorized this!
ちゃんと暗記したはずなのに
Well, you see...
それでね…
分かる
Got it!
Real science isn't any fun if it's just memorization.
本当の理科は　暗記だけじゃ面白くないです
Science absolutely loves when you tell it—
in words, mind you—
君が君であることを知っているよって
ちゃんと言葉にして伝えてあげたら
that you know what it is.
この理科　すごく喜ぶんです
Even in science, you need language skills
to reach other people.
理科にも相手に届く国語力が必要って
I understand that now, Korosensei!
最近　やっと分かってきました　殺せんせー
Now I've done it!
しくじった
How am I supposed to know
アフリカ開発会議の会談の回数なんて分かるかよ
how many times the Tokyo International Conference on African Development has met?!
That was close.
危なかった
Good thing I studied that.
一応　覚えておいて正解だった
Isogai, you little...
磯貝　貴様
Just a fluke.
たまたまだよ
See, my family's pretty poor,
俺んち　結構な貧乏でさ
and when I looked it up out of sympathy for Africa's poverty issues...
アフリカの貧困にちょっと共感して調べてたら…
思い立ったが吉日
No time like the present!
Whaaat?!
実際に現地に連れてかれて　さらに興味が広がっただけだよ
Being taken to the actual location
only made me that much more interested.
「春すぎて夏来にけらし白妙の
"Spring has passed and summer come, it would seem—
from those white hemp robes laid to dry in the sunlight
衣ほすてふ天の香具山」
on Kagu's Heavenly Hill."
Your words are as lovely as your face.
顔だけでなく　言葉も美しい
But a mere sliver of a satisfactory answer does not an aced exam make.
だが　ただいっぺんの会心の解答で　テストの勝敗は決まらない
First Term Final: Math
数学か
Math, eh?
First Term Final: Math
Akabane's in the E Class?
Ｅ組には　赤羽がいたっけ
He came in second on the midterms, after me.
中間の数学は　僕に続いて２位
Quite the showing for an E-Class student.
Ｅ組としては　飛び抜けている
However...
だが
I have no blind spots—not in math nor any other subject.
僕には　数学はもとより　全教科死角はない
Aw...
みんな　目の色変えちゃって　まあ
Everyone's in such a tizzy.
That's not what winning is all about.
勝つってのはそういうことじゃないんだよね
Total victory is scoring an easy win by doing what you always do.
通常運転でさらっと勝ってこその完全勝利
He'll be my sacrifice to the proper way of winning.
正しい勝ち方…
こいつをいけにえにみんなに教えてやるよ
That'll show 'em.
テストは　２日間
Two days of exams.
Assassination, our wager—
暗殺　ギャンブル　全ての結果は丸の数で決まる
everything was riding on how many circles for correct answers we got.
Well, class,
さて　皆さん
your scores in all subjects have arrived.
全教科の採点が届きました
Here goes.
では　発表します
Starting with English:
まずは　英語から
First in the E Class,
Ｅ組の１位
そして　学年でも１位…
and first in the whole year level:
Nakamura Rio!
中村莉桜
E
Nakamura Rio
100 in English
1st in Year 3
Nakamura Rio
100 in English
1st in Year 3
どうや
How's that?
What?!
何
A
Seo Tomoya
95 in English
3rd in Year 3
Seo Tomoya
95 in English
3rd in Year 3
完璧です
Perfect.
君のやる気はむらっ気があるので　心配でしたが
Though your motivation did have a touch of whimsy that worried me.
Well, there's ten billion yen on the line, you know?
何せ賞金１００億懸かってっから
Don't forget about that tentacle now, Korosensei.
触手１本忘れないでよ　殺せんせー
I won't.
もちろんです
Nagisa-kun, you put up a good fight,
渚君も健闘ですが　肝心なところでスペルミスを犯す癖が直ってませんね
but you haven't kicked your habit of making spelling mistakes when it really counts.
E
Shiota Nagisa
91 in English
6th in Year 3
Shiota Nagisa
91 in English
6th in Year 3
Still, top marks in a subject means that's one tentacle down.
さて　しかし　１教科トップを取ったところで　つぶせる触手は１本
喜ぶことができるかは　全教科返した後ですよ
Next up is Japanese:
続いて　国語
Ｅ組１位は…
First in the E Class...
神崎有希子
Kanzaki Yukiko!
However!
…が　しかし　学年１位はＡ組　浅野学秀
First in the year level goes to Asano Gakushuu of the A Class!
A
Asano Gakushuu
100 in Japanese
1st in Year 3
Asano Gakushuu
100 in Japanese
1st in Year 3
E
Kanzaki Yukiko
96 in Japanese
2nd in Year 3
Kanzaki Yukiko
96 in Japanese
2nd in Year 3
Kanzaki-san, you improved tremendously.
神崎さんも　大躍進です　十分ですよ
And that's all that matters.
Asano can really nab those points.
やっぱ点取るな　浅野は
強過ぎ　英語だって　中村と１点差の２位だぜ
He's crazy tough.
Nakamura only beat him in English by a single point.
さすが全国１位
He isn't top of the nation for nothing.
全教科　相変わらず隙がないな
No weaknesses—not in any subject.
They're collectively known as the Big Five...
五英傑なんて並んで呼ばれてるけど…
A
Sakakibara Ren
94 in Japanese
3rd in Year 3
Sakakibara Ren
94 in Japanese
3rd in Year 3
結局は　浅野一人
...but it really comes down to Asano.
あいつを倒さなきゃ　トップは取れないんだ
You've got to take him down,
or you'll never get to the top.
では　続けて返します
Let's move on.
In social studies, first in the E Class goes to Isogai Yuuma-kun.
社会　Ｅ組１位は磯貝悠馬君
そして　学年では…
And as for first in the year level...
Congratulations!
おめでとう
浅野君を抑えて学年１位
You beat out Asano-kun to take the top spot!
Yes!
E
Isogai Yuuma
97 in Social Studies
1st in Year 3
Isogai Yuuma
97 in Social Studies
1st in Year 3
よし
A
Asano Gakushuu
95 in Social Studies
2nd in Year 3
Asano Gakushuu
95 in Social Studies
2nd in Year 3
マニアックな問題が多かった社会で　よくぞこれだけ取りました
An excellent job, especially considering all the fiendish questions you had to deal with!
A
Araki Teppei
93 in Social Studies
3rd in Year 3
Araki Teppei
93 in Social Studies
3rd in Year 3
We're 2 to 1!
これで　２勝１敗
Next up is science...
次は理科　奥田か
Is it Okuda?
First in the E Class for science is Okuda Manami!
理科のＥ組１位は　奥田愛美　そして…
And...
Marvelous!
素晴らしい　学年１位も奥田愛美
First in the year level is also Okuda Manami!
E
Okuda Manami
98 in Science
1st in Year 3
Okuda Manami
98 in Science
1st in Year 3
やった
That's 3 to 1!
３勝１敗
We don't even have to hear how math turned out!
数学の結果を待たずして　Ｅ組が勝ち越し決定
A
Koyama Natsuhiko
95 in Science
2nd in Year 3
Koyama Natsuhiko
95 in Science
2nd in Year 3
We've already won!
Hooray!
Great work, Okuda!
仕事したな　奥田
触手１本　お前のもんだ
That tentacle is yours!
And so is what we're asking for in this little deal!
ってことは　賭けのあれも頂きだな
楽しみ
I can't wait!
So that just leaves math.
あとは　数学だけですね
A
Asano Gakushuu
100 in Math
1st in Year 3
Asano Gakushuu
100 in Math
1st in Year 3
We're 3 to 2 over all five subjects.
５教科勝負　３対２
Ｅ組に負けるなんて
We lost to the E Class.
What could be more humiliating?
こんな屈辱あるか
But it still worked out, Koyama.
でも　よかったじゃないか　小山
I mean, we beat them on total scores.
総合では　標的のあいつに勝てたんだからな
Hmph.
I got my own back against the guy who stole fourth place from me.
俺から総合４位を奪ったやつへのリベンジな
でも　あいつ
But that guy...
勝手に自滅してんだもん
He dug his own grave!
E
Akabane Karma
85 in Math
10th in Year 3
Akabane Karma
85 in Math
10th in Year 3
E
Total Score: 469
13th in Year 3
勝負するまでもないわ　あんな雑魚
Didn't even bother to compete, the scrub.
The A Class is mighty indeed.
さすがにＡ組は強い　５教科総合６位までは独占
They monopolize the top six ranks in overall scores for five subjects.
The best overall scores in the E Class
E
Takebayashi Koutarou
7th in Year 3
E
Kataoka Megu
7th in Year 3
Ｅ組の総合は　片岡さん　竹林君の同点７位が最高でした
were Kataoka-san's and Takebayashi-kun's, both tied for 7th place.
That's to be expected.
当然の結果です
Everyone in the A Class studied like mad, too.
Ａ組の皆も負けず劣らず勉強をした
テストの難易度も上がっていた
The tests' difficulty levels had been greatly increased.
怠け者がついていけるわけがない
No lazy student could be expected to keep up.
何が言いたいの
What are you trying to say?
You thought, "I'm so cool I'll ace these exams, no sweat"?
余裕で勝つ俺カッコイイとか思ってたでしょ
恥ずかしいですね
How mortifying!
A
Total Score: 491
1st in Year 3
Congratulations on retaining your top rank in total score.
個人総合１位キープ　おめでとう
Or so I'd say...
と言いたいところだが
if it weren't for a certain wager you made with the E Class.
何やら　Ｅ組と賭けをしてたそうじゃないか
A wager that you lost.
そして　その賭けに君は負けた
The entire school knows all about your little bet.
全校中に話が広まった以上
You'll have a tough time refusing the E Class's request now.
Ｅ組の要求は　そう簡単には断れないよ
So what will you do?
どうする
Would you like the school to save you?
学校がかばってあげようか
No, thank you.
結構です
私のことを　首輪を着けて飼ってやるとか言ってたね
I believe you said you'd put a collar on me and keep me as a pet,
or attempt to expose my nonexistent secrets.
ありもしない私の秘密を暴こうとしたり…
You certainly talk big for a whelp
who can't even win a bet with his peers.
よく言えたものだね
同い年との賭けにも勝てない未熟者が
Three students have the right
to destroy one of my tentacles:
先生の触手を破壊する権利を得たのは　中村さん　磯貝君　奥田さんの３名
Nakamura-san, Isogai-kun, and Okuda-san.
You contributed nothing—not to this assassination and not to this wager.
暗殺においても　賭けにおいても
君は　今回何の戦力にもなれなかった
分かりましたか
Is that understood?
Those who can't do what they have to
when the time comes for action
やるべきときにやるべきことをやれなかった者は
will find their presence fading in our classroom.
この教室では　存在感を失ってゆく
An assassin who neglects to sharpen his blade is no assassin at all.
やいばを研ぐことを怠った君は　暗殺者じゃない
さびたやいばを自慢げに掲げたただのがきです
He's just a boastful brat swinging around a rusty sword.
Wasn't that a little much?
いいのか　あそこまで言って
ご心配なく　立ち直りが早い方に挫折させました
Don't worry.
I only cut him down because he'll spring back up.
He has been gifted with much talent.
彼は　多くの才能に恵まれている
But those so talented often lack experience.
だが　力ある者は得てして未熟者です
本気でなくても　勝ち続けてしまうために
There's the danger of training him up without knowing real competition,
本当の勝負を知らずに育つ危険がある
since he can keep on winning without ever really trying.
大きな才能は　負ける悔しさを早めに知れば大きく伸びます
If great talent knows the frustration of defeat early on,
it can become even greater.
Exams are an opportunity to correctly teach the meaning of winning and losing, and of strength and weakness.
テストとは　勝敗の意味を　強弱の意味を正しく教えるチャンスなのです
成功と挫折を胸いっぱいに吸い込みなさい　生徒たちよ
Soak up stacked servings of successes and setbacks, my students!
勝つとは何か　負けるとは何か　その意味を　今
Take in now what it means to win and what it means to lose!
It's just so important... and I didn't realize it until the very end.
私が最後まで気付けなかった　とても大事なことだから
All right, class,
さて　皆さん
you had a fine showing in the finals,
素晴らしい成績でした
taking the top spot in three out of five subjects.
５教科で皆さんが取れたトップは　３つです
Shall we get started with the assassination?
早速　暗殺の方を始めましょうか
The top three can choose any tentacle they like.
トップの３人は　どうぞ　ご自由に
３本くらい失っても余裕でしょう
Six, now that would have been rough.
６本はさすがにヤバかったですが
Whoa there, octopus!
おい　待てよ　タコ
We got more than three in the top spot!
５教科トップは３人じゃねえぞ
No, there are three, Terasaka-kun.
３人ですよ　寺坂君
Out of Japanese, English,
social studies, science, and math—
国　英　社　理　数　合わせて…
Huh? Quit playin' dumb!
アホ抜かせ
Five subjects: that's Japanese, English, social studies, science,
５教科っつったら　国　英　社　理
and home ec!
あと　家だろ
H-Home ec?!
か…家庭科
Nobody said what subjects we had to ace!
誰もどの教科とは言ってねえよな
E
Terasaka Ryouma, Yoshida Taisei,
Muramatsu Takuya, Hazama Kirara
100 in Home Ec
1st in Year 3
Terasaka Ryouma, Yoshida Taisei,
Muramatsu Takuya, Hazama Kirara
100 in Home Ec
1st in Year 3
Good thing we all had a hand in this scheme.
クラス全員でやりゃよかった　この作戦
W-Wait a second! Home ec is just—
ちょ…ちょっと待って　家庭科なんて…
Just what?
なんてって
Isn't that a little rude, Korosensei?
失礼じゃねえ　殺せんせー
５教科　最強の家庭科さんにさ
Why, home ec is the toughest subject of them all.
Yeah! Don't break your promise!
そうだぜ　先生　約束守れよ
Four of us scored highest in the most important subject: home ec!
一番重要な家庭科さんで　４人がトップ
That's seven tentacles in all!
合計　触手７本
Seven?! Eeek!
Sev-en! Sev-en! Sev-en!
７本　いや
７本　７本…
それと　殺せんせー　これはみんなで相談したんですが
Oh, and Korosensei, we've been talking...
We'll use our prize from the A Class wager to help with this assassination.
この暗殺に　Ａ組との賭けの戦利品も使わせてもらいます
What?
what？
The end-of-term ceremony came
hot on the heels of our final exams.
期末の後は程なく　１学期の終業式
But there was one thing left for us to do.
けど　僕らには　やるべきことが残っている
Aw, yeah, here he comes.
やっと来たぜ　生徒会長さまがよ
Our oh-so-great student council president.
What do you want?
何の用かな
I'm too busy with the ceremony
to deal with the likes of the E Class.
式の準備で　Ｅ組に構う暇なんてないけど
Not so fast! Aren't you forgettin' something?
おう　待て待て
何か　忘れてんじゃねえのか
We had a bet, Asano, where the winner could make any one demand.
浅野　賭けてたよな
勝った方が　１つ要求できるって
We sent our demand via email.
要求はさっき　メールで送信したけど
I trust you have no complaints?
あれで構わないよな
Don't even try pretendin' it was all just a joke!
まさかいまさら　冗談とか言わねえよな
We could always throw home ec into those five subjects.
何ならよ　５教科の中に家庭科とか入れてやってもいいぜ
'Course, we'd still win!
それでも　勝つけどよ
You sure got the wool pulled over your eyes.
見事にしてやられたわね　あの悪がきどもに
By those punks, no less.
Yes, though their argument was rather tenuous.
ええ　彼らの主張は　詭弁すれすれです
But I'm glad.
でも　私はうれしい
Since home ec isn't on any of the entrance exams,
Main Campus Home Ec Teacher
Yasui Naomichi
(Prefers olive oil)
Main Campus Home Ec Teacher
Yasui Naomichi
(Prefers olive oil)
Main Campus Home Ec Teacher
Yasui Naomichi
(Prefers olive oil)
家庭科のテストは　受験に使わない分　重要度が低い
And now, for the crowning touch: olive oil!
it's not considered important,
so there's a tendency for home ec teachers
よって　問題は教科担任の好みで自由に出題される傾向にある
to put whatever questions they like on the exam.
Don't skimp on the sesame oil!
E-Class Home Ec Teacher
Korosensei
(Prefers sesame oil)
E-Class Home Ec Teacher
Korosensei
(Prefers sesame oil)
E-Class Home Ec Teacher
Korosensei
(Prefers sesame oil)
That puts the E Class at an overwhelming disadvantage,
そうなると　私の授業しか受けていないＥ組の生徒は圧倒的に不利
Really pour it on!
since I'm their only teacher.
They must have done some serious research into past testing trends—
相当　研究したのでしょう
私に一杯食わせるために　ありとあらゆる出題傾向を
all to get the better of me.
With their creative thinking in finding a loophole and the power to focus on attacking it,
盲点を突く自由な発想と一刺しのための集中力
I'd say they fit perfectly in my classroom.
この教室にふさわしい生徒たちです
By the way...
ところで…
Why did we have to stay behind?
何で　私たち　留守番なのかしら
Karasuma-sensei told us not to come to the closing ceremony.
だって　烏間先生が終業式来るなって
Because you're an octopus!
タコがいるせいだわ
Because you're a bitch!
ビッチがいるせいです
Karma!
業
Since when do you attend all-school assemblies?
珍しいな　お前が全校集会来るなんて
If I skip now, it'll look like I'm running away.
だってさ　今ふけると逃げてるみたいで　何か嫌だし
No thanks.
Storehouse Beach!
Strorehouse Bleach
Storehouse…
Storehouse—huh?
Karasuma-sensei!
烏間先生　偽律が気になって　式に集中できないっすよ
The fake Ritsu is too distracting! I can't concentrate!
Suck it up. This is to keep Ritsu
from being exposed as a machine.
こらえてくれ
律が機械だとバレないための工作だ
She's my immediate supervisor's daughter—
直属の上司の娘さんだ
tight-lipped and knows better than to pry.
口は堅いし　詮索もしない
And my supervisor's glad that
Ritsu's tutoring got her grades up.
律の授業で成績が上がったと　上司もご機嫌だ
She's been next to me ever since exams.
俺　テスト中からずっと隣だし
My concentration took such a hit I wound up last in class!
集中できずにクラス最下位になっちまった
E
Sugaya Sousuke
Total Score: 338
95th of 186 in Year 3
Sugaya Sousuke
Total Score: 338
95th of 186 in Year 3
Last in class? That's still around the middle of the year level.
クラスでは最下位でも　学年で見れば　中位の成績
He's come a long way from the very, very bottom.
どんじりから　よくここまで育てたものだ
Now, it may be summer vacation, but don't slack off.
夏休みといっても怠けずに…
Er, uh...
You don't want to wind up like the E Class, you know...
Ｅ組のようにはならないように
Even his usual E Class insults are bombing.
いつものＥ組いじりもウケが悪い
All because the End Class vied for the top spot.
エンドのＥ組がトップ争いをしちゃったから
Korosensei may not have been with us today,
今日　ここに殺せんせーはいないけど
but we stood with our heads held high.
僕らは前を向いて立っていられた
The final exams made all the students more aware of their performance.
今回の期末で　生徒全体の学業意識が向上した
Feeling humiliated and threatened by the E Class,
they'll be driven to strive even harder.
しかも　Ｅ組に対する屈辱や危機感は　なおいっそう奮起する材料になる
Even at this unusual time,
when Earth's existence hangs in the balance,
地球の存亡に関わるような異常なときでも
my educational principles are functioning flawlessly.
私の教育理念は　実に正しく機能している
But that will only be possible as long as we have a true End Class.
…が　それは全てエンドがエンドであってこそ
Measures must be taken while school is out for the summer.
手を打とう…
夏休みの間に
Summer Vacation Guidebook
One for each of you.
一人一冊です
Summer Vacation Guidebook
Again with the ridiculous guidebooks!
出たよ　恒例過剰しおり
It's like an accordion!
アコーディオンみてえだな
And even this isn't enough.
これでも足りないくらいです
The temptations of summer
are simply too many to mention.
夏の誘惑は枚挙にいとまがありませんから
Now, then...
さて
We're about to head into summer vacation,
これより夏休みに入るわけですが
but you have a certain main event coming up.
皆さんには　メーンイベントがありますね
Yeah, the hard-won fruits of our wager!
ああ　賭けで奪ったこれのことね
It's a privilege normally reserved for the class with the best grades—that is, the A Class.
本来は成績優秀クラス　つまり　Ａ組に与えられるはずだった特典ですが
But this time, both the A and E Classes dominated the top fifty.
今回の期末は　トップ５０のほとんどをＡ組とＥ組で独占している
You more than qualify.
君たちにだって　もらう資格はじゅうぶんあります
Summer vacation!
夏休み　椚ヶ丘中学校特別夏期講習　沖縄リゾート２泊３日
The Kunugigaoka Junior High Special Summer Course:
three days and two nights at an Okinawa resort!
Yahoo!
やっほ
Let 'em have that lousy old domestic trip.
あんなしけた国内旅行　くれてやるよ
肝心なときに勝てなくて何が五英傑だ　大笑いだぜ
Some Big Five you are, choking when it matters most!
What a joke!
The only winner you've got is Asano-kun!
勝ててるの浅野君一人じゃない
Will you shut up?
黙ってくれないかな
A beaten dog has no business barking.
負け犬に口なしだ
Sit and stay until I tug your leash.
次に僕がリードを引くまで　お座りしてろ
You'll all pay for this.
この借りは必ず返す
My father will, of course, but before that...
父より先にまずＥ組
I'm coming for you, E Class.
ターゲットはお前らだ
Is that what you'd like to do, then?
で　君たちの希望だと…
Yes. We'll cash in our tentacle-destroying rights
during summer camp.
はい　触手を壊す権利は合宿中に使います
Seven tentacles is a big handicap. But don't stop there!
触手７本の大ハンデでも満足せず
Come after me with raw hunger on this island,
四方を先生の苦手な水で囲まれたこの島を使い
surrounded on all sides by water—my weakness!
万全に貪欲に命を狙う
Let me be honest: you've become formidable students indeed.
正直に認めましょう
君たちは侮れない生徒になった
I've already given you report cards
to show your parents.
親御さんに見せる通知表は先ほど渡しました
These are my report cards for you.
これは　先生からあなたたちへの通知表です
A classroom of double circles:
教室いっぱいの二重丸
we've earned high marks from our target over these past three months.
ターゲットからのこの３カ月のうれしい評価だ
As you make full use of the basics you learned in the first term,
１学期で培った基礎をじゅうぶんに生かし
this summer vacation will be time for plenty of fun, plenty of studying—
夏休みもたくさん遊び　たくさん学び
and, of course, plenty of killing.
そして　たくさん殺しましょう
Class 3-E, Kunugigaoka Junior High: the assassination classroom!
椚ヶ丘中学校　３年Ｅ組暗殺教室　基礎の１学期
Our first term, the fundamentals, is hereby over!
これにて　終業
The sun shines
taiyou ga sasu
太陽が射す　閉ざした瞼の裏側に赤い残像
On the back of my closed eyelids
tozashita mabuta no uragawa ni
I see red afterimages
akai zanzou
With a notebook and a pen in my leather bag
kawa no kaban ni nooto to pen wo
革の鞄に　ノートとペンを　さあ歩き出そう
I go for a walk
saa arukidasou
I keep drawing, but I can't get it to look pretty
kaitemo kaitemo kirei ni naranai
描いても描いても　綺麗にならない
My choice of colors is not to blame
eranda enogu ni tsumi wa nai
選んだ絵の具に　罪はない
I still remember the shooting star I saw last night
kinou no yonaka ni mita nagareboshi mada oboeteiru
昨日の夜中に見た流れ星　まだ覚えている
I was waiting for...
I was waiting for…
Hello shooting-star Hello shooting-star again
Hello, shooting star
Hello, shooting star, again
I was waiting
matteita yo
待っていたよ
The girl of many dreams
yume wo miru ano ko wa zutto
夢を見るあの子はずっと
ここにいるの　Ah　Ah
Is always here
koko ni iru no
あの日のまま　Ah　Ah
Just like you did that day
ano hi no mama
また光って
Shine again
mata hikatte
中学校の家庭分野では　衣食上に関する学習を通して
生活の自立に必要な知識や技術を習得するとともに
家庭の役割について理解を深めます
寺坂君　家庭科を通して生活をよりよくする力を育んでくださいね
次回　暗殺教室　島の時間